John Moffa

Deptford, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/John-Moffa/a5c880740a562012

Experienced Manufacturing Professional with 10 years of acquired skills in many facets of manufacturing and fabrication who has steadily advanced into leadership positions. Computer literate, customer oriented problem solver with an ability to thrive in new situations. An excellent study with a desire for continuous personal growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Foreman

DC Fabricators - Florence, NJ - February 2008 to Present

the Final Oversee and schedule the daily activities of Fabrication and Assembly Departments. Complete audits and document corrective actions. Work alongside Engineers and Project Management to help develop or modify work procedures and tooling to implement efficient work flow. Advise on CBA and grievance related issues. Accomplishments Reduced average Final Assembly time by over 300 hours

■ Qualified Crane Operator/Rigger developed detailed lift plans for various stages of build operations Received V.T. training for root and final welds according to applicable MIL Standards
Selected By Superiors to lead and develop procedures and tooling for one of the largest repair projects in company history and was able reduce initial labor hours by over 79%

Erector

DC Fabricators - Florence, NJ - July 2008 to June 2013

Assemble and perform testing of U.S. Navy Submarine propulsion support equipment during the final stages of fabrication.

Systems include: lube oil, steam, and seawater. Main Condenser, Air Ejector Assembly, and Lube Oil Coolers. Processes include: Hydrostatic testing, Helium leak testing, Construction operation and testing of flushing systems, Hydraulic swaging, Mechanical tube expansion, Bundle Fabrication, component fit up and alignment. Adhere to all MIL-STD and approved procedures and interpret Engineering Drawings and Blueprints.

Complete routine parts inspections to assure quality and maintain tractability.

Utilize calibrated precision equipment to meet specified MFG. Terms, Navy and government specifications. Conduct audits and document preparation in accordance with Quality Programs.

Work in Certified Clean room/ Controlled Area environments.

Mechanic/Fabricator

Engine Distributors, Inc - 2005 to 2008

Worked alongside engineers executing the majority of all fabrication done in the shop, including: welding, the use of machining and steel working equipment. Fabricate as necessary, tooling, or modifications of existing and future product lines.

- •Supervise and aid in assembly process development.
- •Construct diesel and gasoline engines. Convert engines to propane, and natural gas. Incorporate control panels, P.T.O's, clutches, transmissions, hydraulics and D.C. motors for a variety of system requirements.
- •The ability to plan for customer needs and technical requirements.
- Provide technical support and conduct corrective actions as needed.
- •Conduct electrical and mechanical problem solving for warranty and service repair work in accordance with technical manuals.

- •Comprehend engine data analysis.
- •Pull parts from general supply and adjust purchase orders as necessary

Machinist Apprentice

C&P Carbide - 2002 to 2005

Became familiar with Machining equipment, process planning and inspection.

- •Executed parts production, lay out and routine parts and material inspection.
- •Utilize Vertical/Horizontal Milling Machine, Lathe, Surface Grinder, O.D./I.D. Grinder, Radial Drill.
- •Use Comparator, micrometers, calipers, veneers, eye loops, surface finish gages and other calibrated precision equipment to insure product quality.
- •Review Material and perform nondestructive testing as required.
- •Interpret blue prints for technical specs and data utilization.
- •Showed proficiency in Mathematics.
- •Maintained grades in associated apprentice program

EDUCATION

Vocational in design and reading

Technical School 2002 to 2004

Sterling High School 1996 to 2000

SKILLS

Microsoft systems